The frontline intervention for treating anxiety disorders is cognitive behavioural therapy
Phương pháp chính trong điều trị rối loạn lo âu là qua trị liệu nhận thức-hành vi hay CBT
or CBT.
or CBT.
Meta-analyses examining the efficacy of CBT across the anxiety disorders have indicated
Các phân tích tổng hợp về sự hiệu quả của CBT trong các chứng rối loạn lo âu
that CBT is an efficacious treatment across diagnoses, resulting in superior outcomes
chỉ ra rằng CBT là một phương pháp hữu hiệu với mọi loại chẩn đoán,
compared to waitlist control conditions and expectancy control treatments.
cho ra kết quả tốt hơn so với waitlist control conditions và liệu pháp kiểm soát tuổi thọ
When outcomes for specific diagnoses have been examined, outcomes for GAD have been
Khi xem xét kết quả cho từng chẩn đoán, thì kết quả với GAD
found to be superior to outcomes for Social Anxiety Disorder.
tốt hơn nhiều so với kết quả cho rối loạn lo âu xã hội
A systematic review of studies evaluating CBT in the treatment of anxiety disorders
Một hệ thống nhận xét về các nghiên cứu đánh giá CBT trong việc điều trị rối loạn lo âu
in children and adolescents reported an average remission rate (defined as participants being
ở trẻ em và vị thành niên thông báo về tỉ lệ thuyên giảm (người tham gia được chữa khỏi chứng lo âu chính)
free of their primary anxiety diagnosis at post-treatment) of 56.5%.
vào khoảng trung bình 56.5%
This finding has been replicated in other review papers.
Kết quả này cũng được tìm thấy trong các bản báo cáo khác
Although meta-analyses support CBT as the indicated treatment of anxiety disorders in
Tuy các phân tích tổng hợp ủng hộ việc CBT trở thành phương pháp trị rối loạn lo âu chính thức
adults, adolescents and children, there is still a lot of room for improvement – A significant
đối với người lớn, người vị thành niên và trẻ em, thì nó vẫn cần cải thiện thêm
proportion of people are not responding to CBT in the first instance.
Một số lượng lớn bệnh nhân không có phản ứng với CBT vào ban đầu
In addition,
Thêm vào đó, trong người có phản ứng, một bộ phận nhỏ vẫn thỉnh thoảng tái phát các triệu chứng
of those who do respond,
of those who do respond,
a significant minority appear to experience a recurrence in their symptoms over time.
a significant minority appear to experience a recurrence in their symptoms over time.